Remember...
牢记
Why did he kill them? Who are they?
凶手为什么杀死他们？他们是谁？
They have 80 priors between them.
这三人一共有80个前科
They're not connected to Kambura, though. No fingerprints, either.
这些人与坎布拉没有联系，而且也没有发现任何指纹
But CCTV caught the crime.
但是监控拍到了嫌疑人
Let me guess. Cat costume.
我猜他穿了猫服装
Here's your mafia.
这就是黑手党的下场
PERSONAL
个人
TONIGHT, A STAR FELL FROM THE SKY
今晚，一颗流星划过天空
I MADE A WISH
我许了一个愿望
One day, when I was on night duty, a man came to see me.
有一天，当我在夜班时，一个男人来找我
I remember every word he said to me.
我记得他对我说的每句话
"You're going to forget about what happened."
“你会忘记发生了什么事”
"Or you'll disappear," he said.
他说：“否则你会消失的  ”
Hamza Kaymak, right?
哈姆萨·凯马克，对吗？
His photos will be everywhere in half an hour.
他的照片将在半小时内随处可见
Hamza is going to tell them everything he knows. It can't be helped.
哈姆萨会告诉他们他所知道的一切，没办法了
You're going to tell them what you know as well, Vural.
你也要告诉他们你知道什么，乌拉尔
Without forgetting about Ufuk.
不要忘了乌福克
Take a seat, Vural.
坐下，乌拉尔
Hello again.
再次问好
You told me to come see you if I needed anything.
你告诉我如果我有需要时就去找你
Would you kindly die for me?
你愿意为我去死吗？
Firuz, this won't get me in trouble, right?
菲鲁兹，这不会给我带来麻烦吧？
What did you find?
你发现了什么？
I found some blood on the crime scene that didn't belong to the victim.
我在犯罪现场发现了一些不属于受害者的血迹
It probably belongs to the killer.
可能属于杀手
- Is this the DNA report? - Yes.
-这是DNA报告吗？-是的
You think being involved with my daughter makes you immortal?
你以为和我女儿在一起就能让你永生吗？
If I'm not spilling your blood for now,
如果我暂时不杀你
who would you like to take your place?
你想让谁代替你去死？
How about your blood brother?
你该死的兄弟怎么样？
That works, right? That works beautifully.
那行得通，对吗？那行得通
Isn't that the corpse from the forest?
那不是森林里的尸体吗？
Reply to them. Let's see who they are.
回复他们  让我们看看这些人是谁
You know what I wished for?
你知道我许了什么愿望吗？
To be a good person.
做个好人
But...
但……
She remembers everything.
她记得一切
Good morning to you, Agah.
早上好，阿加
No killing anyone today, deal?
今天不杀人，对不对？
Today, we're going to go...
今天，我们要去……
We're going to watch Cemil's show...
我们要去看塞米尔的表演
No off-hours work today.
今天没有下班时间
And we're going to see Feza.
我们要去看望费扎
No, that's tomorrow.
不，那是明天
Fine. Sure.
当然  可以
Sure.
当然
Feza is tomorrow.
费扎是明天
Yes.
是
Sleep, wake, visit Feza.
睡觉，醒来，拜访费扎
GOOD MORNING DEVA. I'M GOING OUT.
早上好德瓦  我出门了
EAT SOMETHING BEFORE YOU LEAVE FOR SCHOOL.
在去学校之前记得吃东西
No, don't do it.
不，不要这样做
Go get a seat on the front row.
去前排找个座位
You ready?
你准备好了吗？
Go on, shoot. The last one was pure luck. Come on!
继续射门，刚才纯属幸运！
I was a goalie for many years. I even played for FC Sishane.
我做了多年守门员，曾经为西甲联赛效力
- I'm shooting the ball. - Go on.
-我要射门了  -来吧
- Goal! - Out!
-进球了！-射偏了！
- How's that out! - That was a goal. You need glasses!
-怎么是射偏了！-那里算进球的，你需要戴眼镜了！
No, the post is from here to there. That was out!
不，球门是从这里到那里的！刚刚那球出界了
Son! How many times have I told you not to play soccer here?
孩子！我告诉过你多少次不要在这里踢足球？
Take your ball and play somewhere else!
带上你的球去别的地方玩！
He's right. So disrespectful!
他说的没错！一点不尊重人！
- You can't play soccer here! - That was a goal!
-你不能在这里踢足球  -那是一个进球
- That was a goal! - Like hell it was. It was out.
-那是一个进球！-进球才怪  明明是界外球
- Dad? - Zuhal? I didn't realize you were here.
-爸爸？-祖哈尔？我没看到你在这里
I came with Cemil.
我和塞米尔一起来的
- Did you know Tayfun? - Of course. Back from Kambura.
-你认识泰丰吗  -当然认识  是我在坎布拉的老朋友
Cemil was devastated, dad. He's grief-stricken.
爸爸  塞米尔收到了重创  他悲痛欲绝
- I can imagine. - He's devastated.
-我能想象到  -他被毁了
I can imagine. They were like brothers.
我能想象到  他们就像兄弟一样
- I should go give my condolences. - Alright. I'll see you at home tonight.
-我应该去哀悼了  -好吧，今晚在家见
- You still remember how to get home? - Do you?
-还记得怎么回家吗？  -你呢？
The ballistics report came today.
弹道报告今天出来了
The bastard blew up the greenhouse using a timed C4 blast.
凶手用定时的C4炸药炸毁了温室
Not a simple C4. A timed one!
不是一个简单的C4炸弹   是个定时炸弹！
He has an armory or something. He could start a war tomorrow.
他有军械库还是什么，完全可以发动战争了
I have something else to tell you.
我还有事要告诉你
I was in a meeting today.
我今天开会时
The prosecutor general and the police commissioner wanted me to pay a visit.
总检察长和警察局长想让我去拜访他们
Unless I make an arrest within one week, we're done.
除非我在一个星期内将其逮捕，否则我们就废了
I'll be the first to go.
我将是第一个离开的
Then, just so you don't get offended, you two will be fired as well.
然后，就这样，没有冒犯的意思，你们两个也会被解雇
This is our last shot.
这是我们的最后的机会了
We have to find something.
我们必须找到一些蛛丝马迹
If we can't, they'll boot us and bring in someone who can.
如果我们做不到，他们会让我们滚蛋然后换个能人
I should ask you if that's clear, but you're pretty bright, so no need.
我应该问你是否清楚，但是你们都很聪明，所以没必要问了
CEM?L HAVRAN  KAMBURANS FOUNDATION
塞米尔·哈夫兰 坎布拉基金会
Easy.
别急
My condolences...
节哀顺变
- Oh dear Cemil, my condolences... - Agah...
-亲爱的塞米尔，节哀  -阿加
What am I to do now?
我现在该怎么办？
He was such an angel.
他真是个好人
- Come stand by me. - Stay strong, son. Stay strong.
-一直支持我  -坚强起来，孩子
- Thanks. - Can't stand against fate.
-谢谢  -不能抗拒命运
- Thank you. - I told him so many times.
-谢谢 -我跟他说了很多遍了
What are you doing, running greenhouses in the middle of nowhere?
你在做什么，在茫茫荒野中开温室？
- Come on, work with me. - Thank you.
-来吧，和我一起工作  -谢谢
I begged him to accept, but he wouldn't. Money meant nothing to him.
我求他来我公司  但他不来  金钱对他没有任何意义
Such a dirty world we live in.
我们生活在一个如此肮脏的世界
Stay strong, son. Can't stand against fate.
坚强，孩子  不能抗拒命运
What fate?
什么命运？
They blew up a florist using a bomb.
他们用炸弹炸毁了一家花店
- Thank you. - You see that casket? It's empty.
-谢谢-看到棺材了吗？是空的
They couldn't find his corpse. It was blown to bits.
他们找不到他的尸体
Get a hold of yourself, Cemil. Whoever did it is bound to get caught.
控制住你自己，塞米尔  不管是谁干的，凶手一定会被抓住
No. No...
不，不
I'll find him. And when I do, that son of a bitch will...
我会找到他的，当我找到他时，一定把那孙子……
Hush! Cemil, we're in a mosque. Don't sin.
嘘！塞米尔，我们在清真寺里，别说了
Agah...
阿加
That bastard stabbed me in the heart.
那个混蛋刺伤了我的心
- How did you know the departed? - He was a good man.
-你怎么认识死者的？-他是个好人
-你怎么知道死者的？-他是个好人
- Do you give him your blessing? - We do.
-祝福他了吗?  -祝福他
Al-Fatiha!
天父！
This girl,
这个女孩
the girl Tayyar raped...
塔亚尔强奸的……女孩
What are you thinking?
你在想什么？
What did Vural say?
乌拉尔怎么说？
The fireman, what was his name? Halis.
消防员，他叫什么名字？哈里斯
- He's dead, right? - Yes?
-他死了吧？-是吗？
- He knew about what happened. - If Vural's telling the truth. Yes.
-他知道发生了什么  -如果乌拉尔说的是真的
So Halis tampered with the report to protect Ufuk.
因此，哈里斯篡改了这份报告，以保护乌福克
So he knew about the girl. Ufuk must've told him.
那么他知道那个女孩  乌福克一定告诉过他
I'm wracking my brain...
我在想……
Ufuk came to us of his own volition. He wanted to tell us everything.
乌福克自愿来这里，告诉我们一切
- Why didn't he ever mention that girl? - You saw how he was.
-他为什么不提那个女孩？-你也看到他了
How can we know what's going through Ufuk's mind?
我们怎么知道乌夫克在想什么？
Anyway. Let's get back to how Halis knows about the girl.
无论如何，让我们回到哈里斯对女孩了解的话题
Either Ufuk told him, or he'd heard it somewhere else.
乌福克告诉了他，或者他在其他地方听说了
- Kambura is a small place, after all. - Yes...
-毕竟坎布拉是个小地方  -是的
Alright.
好的
If Halis knew...
如果哈里斯知道
Why wouldn't anyone else know?
为什么别人都不知道？
What if they...
如果他们……
What if
如果
they all knew about the rape,
他们都知道强奸，
but didn't say or do anything?
但什么都没说也什么都没做？
The girl is speaking to me. See what she's saying?
这个女孩在跟我说话  看到她说什么了吗？
Save me, Nevra.
内芙拉，救救我
I MET A GIRL TODAY HER NAME IS NEVRA YILMAZ
我今天遇到一个女孩  她叫内芙拉·艾尔玛斯
I TRUST ONLY HER BECAUSE NEVRA GETS ME
我只相信她  因为内芙拉了解我
She's been speaking to me through him this whole time.
她一直都在和我说话
All of it.
所有这些都是对我说的
So Tayyar...
那么塔亚尔……
Raped this girl. He raped her ten years ago.
强奸了这个女孩  他十年前强奸了她
He threatened and scared her somehow.
他以某种方式威胁并恐吓她
She didn't want to come forward.
她不想挺身而出
So all these murders are revenge for that girl.
所以所有这些谋杀都是为女孩复仇
If we find the girl, we will have found him.
如果我们找到那个女孩，我们将会找到他
Whoever's committing the murders is someone who knows the girl.
凶手一定认识这个女孩
Just as Ufuk killed the rapist...
就像乌福克杀死了强奸犯一样……
He's killing all the people who stood by and did nothing.
他正在杀所有袖手旁观的人
- So they're the silent perpetrators. - Exactly. Exactly.
-所以他们是沉默的肇事者  -正是这样
We need to find her. We should go to Kambura immediately.
我们需要找到她  我们应该立即去坎布拉
And do what?
做什么呢？
Get on the PA system and ask the whole town whom Tayyar raped?
用广播喇叭问所有人塔亚尔强奸了谁？
No, not like that.
不，不是那样
But if we assume that she was a young girl ten years ago,
但是如果我们假设她十年前是个年轻女孩，
I'm going to gather all women between the ages of 25 and 50
那么我将所有25至50岁之间的女性整理出来
in the county and talk to them.
在村子里和她们谈谈
Do you think it will work?
你认为这行得通吗？
Do you have any other suggestions?
你有什么其他的建议？
Agah? Agah!
阿加？阿加？
Taci?
塔奇？
I thought I knew you when I saw you at a distance.
我在远处看到你时就觉得是你
- Years go by so fast, huh, Agah? - Yes. They do.
-岁月流逝太快了  -是的
Do you have some time? Let's go sit somewhere.
你有时间吗  我们去别的地方
- No, I wasn't going to... - Wasn't going to what?
-不，我不打算……  -不打算做什么？
- I have an appointment. - With whom?
-我有个约会  -和谁约会？
With myself.
和我自己
Come on. I've found you again after all these years.
来吧，过了这么多年我们又见面了
I'm not letting go. I'm having a terrible day as it is.
我不放你走  我今天过得很糟糕
It's about Tayfun... He was so young.
泰丰……他还很年轻
- Cemil's devastated, of course. - I know. Devastated, yes.
-当然  对塞米尔是毁灭性的打击  -是的，毁灭性
Curse the bastard that did it!
诅咒那个凶手不得好死
Come on, don't play hard to get. We can take my car.
来吧，别装了 坐我的车走
My car's right over there. Son, bring my car over.
我的车就在那边  孩子，把我的车开过来
- Sure, if you really want to. - Let's go.
-当然可以，如果你想开车的话  -我们走吧
- When one's time has come... - Excuse me?
-当一个人的时间到了……  -什么？
My bag's in the car. I should go fetch it.
我的包在车里，我应该去拿一下
Deren Koro?lu...
德仁·科罗鲁
I MET A GIRL TODAY
我今天遇到一个女孩
As the founding members of the Dog Slayer Fan Club...
作为狗杀手粉丝俱乐部的初始成员
We formally accept you into our ranks.
我们正式接受你加入我们
Welcome, all of you.
欢迎大家
Keeping true to tradition, we're going to celebrate
秉承传统，我们将要和
with some Dog Slayer.
狗杀手一起庆祝
A few Dog Slayers, in fact.
实际上，有一些狗杀手
- Arda, right? - Yes.
-阿尔达，对吗？-是
It's really strange...
真的很奇怪
It's a really weird coincidence.
这真是一个奇怪的巧合
You're strolling through the forest, looking to take some footage.
你正在森林中漫步，希望拍摄一些照片素材
And what do you know, you run into a corpse.
但世事难料，遇到了一具尸体
That's exactly what happened. We were really surprised, as well.
就是这样  我们也很惊讶
It's really hard to get hold of a body.
真的很难控制身体
- We found one hanging from a tree. - They apparently grow on trees, right?
-我们在树上发现了一个悬吊物  -它们显然长在树上，对吗？
Alright, then.
那好吧
Cheers to Dog Slayer.
敬狗杀手
So? What do we do now?
那我们现在做什么？
Art.
艺术
- What's this? - Tomorrow's article.
-这是什么？-明天的文章
You think this is why I called you over?
你以为这就是我给你打电话的原因吗？
I have something else to ask you.
我还有事要问你
Like what?
什么问题？
Like are you alright?
类似你还好吗？
I'm fine, thank you.
我很好，谢谢你
We can cover you if you need some vacation time.
如果你需要一些休假时间，包在我们身上
No...
不用
I'm serious. We're doing alright.
我是认真的  我们现在很好
The tourism agencies keep calling us, asking us to send someone on vacation.
旅行社不断打电话给我们，要我们派人去度假
It's advertising for them. You can take a few days off.
这是他们的广告  你可以休息几天
Take in the sights, have some delicious food.
参观景点，吃点美味的食物
And when you come back, write about it.
当你回来时，写篇文章
It will do you good, won't it?
这对你有好处，不是吗？
- I'm already good. - You're already good? Are you now?
-我已经很好了  -你已经很好了吗？
What's this then?
那这是什么？
What's this you wrote?
你写的是什么？
Look at this.
看这个
Fake fire brigade reports.
假消防队报告
Fake health bills.
假医疗账单
Heavy penal court judges taking bribes.
重刑法院法官受贿
And that's not the half of it. It goes on and on.
而且这只是一小部分，没完没了
I'll read out some. Where was that?
我读一些给你听  在哪里？
Here.
这里
Listen.
听
"Perhaps, including the civilian administrative chief,"
“也许包括平民行政首长”
every single prominent person in the county knew about the incident.
县里每个着名人物都知道这件事
Which is why this doesn't concern only Kambura.
这就是为什么这不仅仅与坎布拉有关
If there is a crime,
如果真的有犯罪
and if that crime was whitewashed,
如果该罪行被粉饰，
this concerns the whole country.
这就关系到整个国家
And if that crime is the killing of a family of seven in a fire,
如果那个罪行是杀死7口之家，
"we were all burned in that fire. We just don't realize it."
“那么我们都被那场大火烧死了，我们只是没有意识到”
What happened to you, son?
孩子  你怎么了
What do you mean? I'm doing my job.
什么意思？  我在做我的工作
- You used to write such pretty things. - Yes.
-你以前写过很漂亮的文章-是的
I used to write about shit that didn't matter.
我以前经常写无所谓的垃圾文
Listen, Ates. I can't publish this article.
听着，阿提斯  我无法发表这篇文章
I know what will happen to me if I chose to publish this article.
我知道如果我选择发表这篇文章将会对我产生什么影响
I'll get 40 phone calls within the minute.
我一分钟会接到40个电话
Forgive me, but I don't have time for that.
原谅我，但我没有时间接
Then...
那么……
You forgive me as well.
也请原谅我
Look, Ates...
听好，阿提斯
I'll put it in terms you'll understand.
我会用你能理解的语言来表达
If you insist on getting this article published,
如果你坚持让这篇文章发表，
you can no longer work for this paper. You got that?
你就不能在这家报社工作了  你明白了？
I never worked for this paper.
我从未为这家报社工作
I'm just now starting to work here. I haven't done any real work in years.
我现在才刚刚开始  我多年来从没有做过任何真正意义上的工作
But we're not in the same industry.
但是我们不在同一个行业
That's why I bid you good luck...
这就是为什么我要祝你好运
- And lots of profit!  - Ates! Ates!
-祝公司能赚很多钱！-阿提斯！阿提斯！
Ates, get back here!
阿提斯  回来！
Enjoy your day, guys.
祝大家玩的开心
- Hello? - Hello?
-喂？-喂？
- Nevra, I just resigned. - Congratulations. How does it feel?
-内芙拉，我刚辞职了 -恭喜，你的感觉如何？
Like I'm myself.
感觉像我自己
I'm feeling like myself for the first time in a long while.
很长时间以来第一次感觉像自己
I'm happy to hear that.
我很高兴听到这个消息
- Can I call you back later? - Sure.
-我可以等下再打给你吗？-当然可以
Finally!
终于！
It will do you good, Ates!
这对你有好处，阿提斯！
We sent word to every house. But some of them are at work,
我们向每户人家都传达了消息  但是有些人在上班
- All the others are inside. - Alright. Thank you.
-其他人都在里面  -好，谢谢
- Did you put the board up? - Yes.
-你把板子放好了吗-是的
All you're achieving right now is scaring those people, and that's it.
你现在所做的就是吓唬那些人，仅此而已
Ladies. We'll ask the men to leave.
女士们，我们请男人们离开
They'll leave us alone in here. Woman to woman.
他们会出去  我们来谈谈
- But I'd like to... - We'll be fast. Don't worry.
-但我想……-我们会很快的  别担心
Come on, let's have some tea together. I'm buying. Come on.
来吧，让我们一起喝杯茶吧
My name is Nevra. Nevra Y?lmaz.
我是内芙拉·艾尔玛斯
We know who you are. We've been watching you on TV.
我们知道你是谁  电视上看到过你
Good. Good.
很好
Then you also should know that I lived here for a short while.
那你们也应该知道我在这里住过一阵
You could say I'm a Kamburan, in a way.
也可以说我是一个坎布兰人
I'd like you to share
我希望你们能够
everything I say here today with your friends at home.
把我今天说的话和你们的家人及朋友分享
- Is that a deal? - Sure, we'll tell them.
-可以吗？-当然，我们会告诉他们
But I have food cooking at home. Whatever it is, make it quick.
但是我家里煮着饭，不管你要说什么，快点说
I'd like you to take out your phones and save this number to your contacts.
我希望你拿出手机并将此号码保存到你的联系人中
You can call this number 24/7, whenever you want.
你随时可以拨打此号码
Go on.
继续
We have food cooking at home. We wouldn't want them to get burnt.
我们家里还煮着饭，我们不想让它烧糊
Do you have it? Save it as Nevra the Cop.
保存了吗？保存为内芙拉警察
Ladies...
女士们
Today, or yesterday, or a year ago...
今天或昨天或一年前
Or some day in the past, no matter when.
或过去的某一天，无论何时
If you've been harassed or raped, please call this number.
如果你遭到骚扰或强奸，请拨打此电话
I'll be the only one who answers the phone,
我将是唯一接听电话的人，
and I'll be the only one who'll know who's called.
我将是唯一知道你名字的人
I give you my word as a woman.
我以女性的身份向您保证
What if they do call? What will you do about it?
如果他们打来电话怎么办？你会怎么做？
Whatever the caller wants me to.
来电者想要我做什么
Not more, not less.
我就做什么
Are you sick? Caught a cold or something?
你生病了？感冒了？
Yes. I'll tell you about it some time.
是的，我等下会告诉你的
- So? You live here now? - Yeah.
-那么  你现在住在这里吗？-是的
No more home.
没别的家了
This is my home.
这就是我的家
Isn't it hard?
不难吗？
Sometimes, sure.
有时候是的
But it's automatic. Everything here's automatic.
但这是自动的  一切都是自动的
Automatic...
自动……
Press a button, and it goes. Press a button, and it stops.
按下一个按钮它就走，再按一个就停下
The boys keep asking me...
孩子们经常会问我
"Dad, what do you do all alone out at sea?"
“爸爸，你一个人住在海上干什么？”
They're concerned. Concerned that I might die.
他们担心我可能会死
- I'm sick of people. - You don't say.
-我讨厌别人  -还用说
What?
什么？
You used to want people around all the time. Didn't you?
你过去身边总是有人，不是吗？
You would ask us to picnic on weekends. You wouldn't let it go.
你会邀请我们周末去野餐  你不会放过任何机会
I did. It's been so long.
是的  已经很久了
I'm so old now, Agah.
我很老了，??阿加
I learned only one thing in this life.
我这辈子只学了一件事
You know what that is?
你知道那是什么吗？
Keep away from people.
远离人
Yeah? Why?
是吗？为什么？
Either they'll hurt you, or you'll hurt them.
他们会伤害你，或者你会伤害他们
Two people coming together is like smashing two eggs together.
两个人在一起就像两个鸡蛋互砸一样
One of them is bound to get smashed.
其中之一势必将粉碎
You know why I wanted to talk to you today, Agah?
你知道为什么我今天想和你聊聊吗？阿加？
- You know the killer? - What killer?
-你知道杀手吗？-什么杀手？
The one who killed Tayfun.
杀死泰丰的人
He shot lots of people around here, as well.
他也在这附近杀了很多人
I overheard them talking at the funeral.
我听见他们在葬礼上讨论
That's when I was reminded of it. That's also when I ran into you.
那时我想起来了，也就是我遇见你的那一刻
You worked at courthouses for years. You must still have some connections.
你在法院工作了多年  你一定还保持联系
People with priors. Ex-prisoners. I thought maybe...
有前科的人  进过监狱的人 我想可能……
Maybe what, Taci?
也许什么，塔奇 ？
Could you find me a killer, Agah?
也许你能为我找出杀手，阿加
Excuse me?
什么？
A killer.
杀手
For you.
为你
What do you mean, they gathered up the women? What does she want?
什么意思，聚集了这些女人？她想要什么？
She's supposedly going to find the girl that Tayyar raped.
据说她要找到塔亚尔强奸的那个女孩
Oh God!
天啊！
Alright, you hold tight. I'll think of something.
好吧，你稳住  我想想办法
Are they gone now? Nevra and the others?
他们现在走了吗？内芙拉他们？
They're gone. They stopped by the burnt-down house.
他们走了  又去被烧毁的房子了
Took some more photos.
拍了一些照片
What are they looking for at that house?
他们在那房子找什么？
Vural...
乌拉尔……
Tear it down.
拆了它
Get a bulldozer today. Tear the house down.
今天就买一辆推土机  把房子推了
Bury the rubble.
碎砖瓦都埋起来
I don't want them getting anything out of that house.
我不想让他们从那所房子里得到任何东西
Level the place. You got that?
把那房子夷为平地  明白了吗？
Of course.
明白
Forgive me, Zuhal.
原谅我，祖哈尔
They come to me with the most ridiculous questions.
他们找我问一个愚蠢的问题
You know how I feel sometimes?
你知道有时候我是什么感觉吗？
As though they loaded the whole world on my back,
仿佛他们把整个世界都压在我的背上，
and they keep telling me to get a move on.
并且不断让我继续前进
Throw off your burden, then. Throw it off and be free.
那么，甩掉你的负担吧  扔掉它，重获自由
How am I supposed to do that? I live in that world also.
我应该怎么做？我还生活在那个世界里
Fine. Leave some of it for me, then. Let me carry some of it.
好吧  负担也给我一些，我们一起背
You're already carrying me. That's more than enough.
你已经在背负我了  那已经足够了
I get it now.
我明白了
You get what?
明白什么了？
Why my dad loves you so much.
为什么我爸爸这么爱你
So?
怎么？
You're going to die, huh?
你快死了吧？
I'm going to die, alright...
是的  我快死了……
But it's proving to be very painful.
但事实证明，这是非常痛苦的
It's a prick of an illness.
这是一种疾病
It's seen predominantly in Turkish people.
主要出现在土耳其人身上
I wonder why.
我想知道为什么
There are these pockets of air in the lungs.
肺里有这些空气囊
Little stones form inside them. Like grains of sand.
里面会形成沙粒一样的结石
What's it called?
什么病？
Alveolar Microlithiasis.
肺泡微结石症
I see.
知道了
It's seen in Turkish people, but the name's not in Turkish.
是在土耳其人身上发现的  但是却不是以土耳其语命名
Yes. Well...
是的
That's why, Agah... I want to die.
这就是为什么，阿加，我想死
I can't take it anymore.
我受不了了
I have my wits about me still.
我还算有点理智
My arms and legs still work. I want to go while I still have all that.
我的胳膊和腿也还能用  我想在我仍然能自理的时候离开
I can't kill myself.
我不能自杀
I tried. I tried time and again.
我试过一次又一次
But life grabs you so tightly that it's impossible to get free.
但是生活紧紧地抓住了你，以至于无法获得自由
Life... Wraps itself around your neck.
生活环绕在你的脖子上
I'd like someone to come...
我希望有人……
Put a bullet in my spine, and set me free.
把子弹打在我的脊椎上，让我自由
You're right...
你是对的……
I always loved this side of yours.
我一直喜欢你这点
You used to say that if you studied law, you would want to become
你曾经说过，如果你学习法律
neither prosecutor, nor judge, nor lawyer.
你既不想做检察官，也不想做法官或律师
- I'd like to become a notary. - Yes!
-我想当公证人-是的！
Being a notary is perfect for you.
做公证人对你来说简直完美
This is what being a notary is like. A notary doesn't ask questions.
公证人就是这样  公证人不问问题
He doesn't judge you...
他不审判你
He bears witness, puts down his seal, then turns around and leaves.
公证，盖章，然后转身离开
So, Agah?
所以  阿加？
Is there someone who'd kill me? Could you find me someone?
有没有人愿意杀我的？你能找到这个人吗？
How are you doing?
你好吗？
You can imagine.
你可以想象
Any news?
有什么消息吗？
- No. - What do you mean, no?
-没有  -你是什么意思，没有？
Not one fucking change.
没有一点改变
They made a mistake with the list.
他们把清单弄错了
The heart was compatible with someone else.
心脏不匹配
Alright. Fine.
好吧
How's the little Sefa doing?
小塞法过得好吗？
As you can see. He's tired. Sleeping.
如你所见  他睡着了
I didn't want to wake him up.
我不想叫醒他
Good. Good.
好
- It was so funny the other day. - What was?
-前几天真有趣  -怎么了？
The boys at the station were having a ball.
局里的男孩们正在打球
Come on, not you!
不是吧！
What do you mean, "around 5.11 in height"?
你是什么意思，“身高1米56”？
Not 6 feet. 5.11.
不是1米83  而是1米56
I could tell from your voice.
我能从你的声音中听出来
You were in a panic for letting him get a way.
你因他得逞而惊慌失措
How could I not be? It happened again after all these years.
怎么会不惊慌  这么多年之后情景重现
It says 5.11 in his report.
他的报告中说1米56
Not around 5.11, 5.11 exactly.
不是大约1米56  而是正好1米56
But I was more concerned about your situation.
但我更担心你的情况
"I let him get away again," I thought. "There has to be someone helping him."
“我让他又逃走了，”我想  “肯定有人在帮他  ”
Another gunfight will break out. Shots will be fired yet again.
另一场枪战即将爆发  枪声会再次响起
I was terrified.
我吓坏了
- I sometimes wish you'd left me there. - Stop talking nonsense.
-有时候我希望你把我留在那里-别胡说八道
I'm serious.
我是认真的
I wish you'd leave me there so I could fucking die.
我希望你能把我留在那里，这样我就可以死掉了
You jumped into the fray.
你跳入了困境
I was out of bullets. They were about to put one in my head.
我没子弹了  他们就要开枪打我的时候
You arrived just like Superman.
你就像超人一样到达
You should have asked.
你应该问
"Do you want to live?"
“你想活着吗？”
"Should I save your life?"
“我应该救你的命吗？”
- Like my life's worth anything. - Of course it is.
-就像我的生命有意义一样-当然有意义
You got married.
你结婚了
Had a beautiful boy. He's in there as we speak.
有了一个漂亮的孩子  我们说话的时候就在那里
Gave him Sefa as a name. My boy.
给他起名叫做塞法
Then your wife couldn't stand you and ran away.
然后你的妻子受不了你逃跑了
And you started hating all women.
然后你开始讨厌所有女人
Your life was fucked. What else could you ask for?
你的生活很糟，你还能要求什么？
- As though yours wasn't. - We're talking about you for now.
-好像你的不糟  -我们现在说的是你
Don't you have a home or something? Go home.
你没有家吗？回家吧
I do.
我有
I do have a home, but there's no one in it.
我有家，但家里没有人
You took that one girl home.
你带那个女孩回了家
We did it on the floor. It doesn't count.
我们是在地板上做的  那不算
Esin?
内斯林？
What is it, Vural?
什么事，乌拉尔？
- Blown tyre again? - No, it's not that.
-轮胎又爆了吗-不是
I was told you were given something for safekeeping.
有人告诉我你有东西要妥善保管
Safekeeping?
保管？
You know how they're tearing the house down?
你知道他们把房子拆掉了吗？
You took something from the house. What did you take?
你从屋子里拿走了东西 你拿了什么？
Have you completely lost it? Is that why you came all the way here?
你有病吗？这就是为什么你一路跟到这里吗？
Nothing will come out of that house.
房子里的任何东西都不能带出来
It's all headed underground.
都要埋到地下
Who says?
谁说的？
Cemil?
塞米尔？
Tell hi to Cemil for me.
给塞米尔问好
Give back what you took and we'll throw it out for you.
把你拿走的东西交出来，我们会为你扔掉
Sadi? What are you doing, son?
萨迪，你在做什么，孩子？
I'll tell your mom! Give it back!
我要告诉你妈妈！还给我！
- Come on, don't make this any harder. - Vural, stop snooping!
-拜托，别再为难了  -乌拉尔  快停下！
- Stop going through my stuff! - Give back whatever it is you took.
-别再看我的东西了！-把你拿走的东西交出来
You're making a big mistake. Get out of my car!
你犯了个大错误  下车！
Auntie, what are you doing? Auntie! Auntie!
阿姨，你在做什么？阿姨！
Auntie, what are you doing?
阿姨  你在做什么？
I told you, you were making a big mistake.
我告诉你，你犯了个大错误
You're going to break my neck!
你会扭断我的脖子的！
You'll be just fine. What did I tell you?
你会没事的  我刚刚不是告诉你了吗？
- I told you to get lost! - Take it down. I'm begging you!
-我叫你滚蛋！-求求你了，我求求你！
Do you think we're children? Do you think this is all a game?
你认为我们是孩子吗？你认为这都是游戏吗？
- I'm asking you nicely. - You can stop asking.
-我现在很客气的请求你  -你不用求了
Let's start moving.
我们走吧
- Auntie! Let me go! - You're strangling me!
-阿姨，放开我-你要勒死我了！
- Auntie, let me go! - Auntie, let us go! I'm begging you!
-阿姨，让我走！-阿姨，让我们走！求你了！
Bastards!
混蛋！
Now get the fuck out of my face.
现在都他妈给我滚
You'll pay for that, Nesrin. You'll pay for that!
你将为此付出代价，内斯林  你将为此付出代价！
Move, you idiot!
走  白痴！
That's what you get, little shits!
这就是你们的报应，小混蛋！
I must've dozed off, Nesrin.
我一定是打瞌睡了，内斯琳
They're tearing down the house you threw a stone at.
他们把山上的房子拆了
They're leveling it.
夷为平地
It'll all be gone by tomorrow.
明天一切都会消失
But...
但……
Everyone will forget about it anyway.
每个人都会忘记它
I wanted you to know.
我想让你知道
If, after all these years,
这些年来，如果
your conscience is plaguing you for throwing that stone...
你的良心因你扔石头困扰着你……
I went there...
我去了那儿……
And I brought you that stone so that your pain isn't for naught.
我给你带来了那块石头，所以你的痛苦不是毫无意义的
Sleep well.
好好睡
- Cheers. - Cheers.
-干杯-干杯
- What brings you here? - I just felt like it.
-什么风把你刮来了？-我只是喜欢这里
Welcome, then.
那就欢迎你
Welcome, but what's wrong with you?
欢迎，但是你怎么了？
What's right with me, Timur?
帖木儿，我怎么了？
A psycho killer is out on the loose...
一个变态杀手在逃
And here I am enjoying myself, having raki with you.
而我在这里和葡萄酒
- Let's enjoy ourselves, then. - Let's.
-尽情享受吧  -享受吧
Do you still think about Nevra?
你还想内芙拉吗？
No.
没有
It's over.
结束了
- Sure. If you say so. - It is.
-当然  如果你这样说  -是的
It was a childish fantasy. It's over. I mean...
那是一个孩子气的幻想  已经结束了  我是说……
I was kidding myself.
我是在逗自己玩
I thought there was something, but it was a mistake.
我以为有什么感觉，但那是个错误
Officer Nevra's world has no place in it for me.
内芙拉警官的世界没有我的位置
Plus, look what happened. Look who she's with now.
另外，看看发生了什么  看看她现在和谁在一起
So what? Was your crazy Ceyda any better?
那又怎样？你那个疯狂的杰伊达好点了吗？
Getting a divorce from her wasn't fun, was it?
和她离婚不好玩，对吧?
You're right.
是的
Never mind all that. How are the kids doing?
没关系，孩子们过得怎么样？
Good. They're doing good.
好  他们过得不错
They start running away whenever they see me. But they're good.
他们一见到他们就躲开，但是他们很好
Timur...
帖木儿
- I'm going to give my resignation. - What are you talking about?
-我要辞职了 -你在说什么？
If I can't catch this guy, I shouldn't be in this line of business.
如果我不能抓住这个人，我就不应该从事这个行业
If I can't catch him, they'll take her away anyway.
如果我抓不到凶手，他们会把她带走的
Thanks.
谢谢
I couldn't bear that.
我不能忍受
Tolga... Let me to tell you something.
托尔加  让我告诉你一些事
You remember when you told me
你记得你告诉过我
that Nevra wanted to give her resignation but you refused?
内芙拉想辞职，但你拒绝了？
I'm refusing yours, brother.
我拒绝你  兄弟
I'm refusing your letter of resignation.
我拒绝你的辞呈
You're going to find that bastard.
你一定能抓到凶手
And then, you're going to put him behind bars.
然后，你要把他关在牢里
- You got that? - Got it, Chief.
-你明白了吗  -知道了
You know what I want to do? I want to go on a vacation with you.
你知道我想做什么吗？我想和你一起度假
Just for two-three days. What do you say?
就两三天，你觉得怎么样？
I don't know. There's Zuhal and Deva. Things come up.
不好说啊  祖哈尔和德瓦怎么办
They can take care of themselves. What do you say? Let's go.
他们可以照顾自己的  你觉得怎么样？我们一起去吧
I don't know.
我不知道
- There's nothing to know. - Can I ask you something?
-没什么可知道的  -我能问你一件事吗？
You know how you told me your husband...
你知道你是怎么告诉我你丈夫……
That your departed husband was in an accident?
你丈夫因意外去世的吗？
Can we not talk about that right now?
我们现在能不谈论这个吗？
I just want to ask something.
我只想问一点
You can ask if you promise to come on a vacation with me.
如果你答应和我去度假的话我就让你问
Alright.
好的
You know how he caused the accident because he wanted to die?
你知道他造成了意外是因为他想死
What do you think would happen if he'd failed
你认为如果他在事故中自杀
to kill himself with that accident?
失败了会怎么样？
I can answer that right away. He'd die again and again every day.
我可以马上回答你  他会每天都尝试去死
Every day for the rest of his life.
终生的每一天
I see.
我懂了
Why do you ask?
你为什么要问？
I made a decision today.
我今天做了个决定
I was wondering if I made the right one.
我想知道我做的是否正确
That's why I asked.
这就是为什么我问
- What was this decision? - I want to tell you something.
-这个决定是什么？-我想告诉你一些事情
And the only one I've shared it with so far is my cat.
到目前为止，我唯一与之分享的是我的猫
Now I'm sharing it with you.
现在我要和你分享
I'm really scared of death.
我真的很怕死
- Everyone is. - Sure. I know that.
-每个人都是  -当然，我知道
Today, I decided what to do with that fear.
今天，我决定如何应对这种恐惧
I told you I was at a funeral today.
我和你说过我今天在葬礼上
I kicked a ball around with some kids in the courtyard of the mosque.
我和几个孩子在清真寺的院子里踢球
Something happened then.
然后有事发生了
I felt something.
我感觉到了什么
I said to myself: "Agah, don't be scared of being afraid."
我对自己说：“阿加，别因害怕而感到害怕”
"Instead of fearing death and dying every day,
“与其每天害怕死亡
fear death, sure, but live every day."
不如活好每一天”
How's that?
怎么样？
- Beautiful. - Beautiful.
-说得好  -说得好
To health.
敬健康
Drop the phone please.
请放下手机
You've been staring at it since you walked in.
你来了之后就一直盯着它
Nobody called.
没有人打电话
What did you expect? She's kept quiet for ten years.
你有什么期望？她已经沉默了十年
Would she break her silence because you came along?
因为你来了，她就会打破沉默吗？
Give it some time. Be patient.
给她一点时间  耐心点
Think how hard it must be for her.
想想对她来说有多难
You're right.
你是对的
You're right. What are you doing?
你是对的，你在做什么？
Creating a media empire for myself.
为自己打造一个媒体帝国
I'm starting a Youtube channel.
我正在创建一个YouTube频道
- Unknown caller. - Answer it. Go on, answer it.
-未知来电  -接啊，快接
Hello?
喂？
Yes, this is her. I don't...
是的，是我，我……
Miss, please calm down.  Please stop shouting. I'm listening.
小姐  请冷静点  不要喊  我在听
What?
什么？
Can you tell me who did it?
你能告诉我是谁做的吗？
Alright.
好的
Can we meet? It will...
我们可以见面吗？
It will take me some time to drive to Kambura from Istanbul.
从伊斯坦布尔开车到坎布拉需要一些时间
Is that so?
是吗？
Alright.
好的
Yes. Alright. I'm on my way.
好的，我现在过去
She talked about a rape.
她谈到强奸
Tayyar Kaymak.
塔亚尔·凯马克
- I'm going. - You're going now?
-我要走了 -现在吗？
Where is she?
她在哪？
- Have you been waiting long? - It's alright, it's just that...
-等了很久吗？ -没事  只是……
The station was really crowded.
车站真的很挤
So many buildings. All on top of each other.
如此多的建筑物相互重叠
How do you live here?
你在这里怎么生活？
It's pretty hard, to be honest.
老实说这很难
Yeliz...
耶利兹
- Can I call you Yeliz? - Yes, yes, of course.
-我可以叫给你耶利兹吗-当然可以
- You can call me Nevra. - Alright.
-你可以叫我内芙拉-好的
Were you already going to come here? Do you have relatives here or something?
你本来就准备来这里吗？你在这里有亲戚吗？
No. When I told him I was going to talk to you,
当我告诉他我要和你谈的时候，
my husband kicked me out of the house.
我丈夫把我踢出了家门
I see.
我懂了
- Do you have children? - No. We couldn't have children.
-你有孩子吗？-不，我们没办法怀孩子
Alright. Here's what we're going to do.
好了  这就是我们要做的
Come in.
进来吧
This way.
这边
- May I? - Go on. Make yourself at home.
-可以吗？-来吧  像在家里一样
You can stay here for the night. We'll figure it out tomorrow.
你可以在这里过夜  我们明天会解决的
Go on. Make yourself at home.
来吧  就像在自己家一样
- Hello? - Hello?
-喂？-喂？
Hello? Nevra? I was worried. You weren't answering your phone.
喂？内芙拉？我很担心  你没有接电话
We just got home.
我们刚到家
She's staying at my place for the night.
她在我家过夜
She doesn't have anyone to turn to.
他们有任何人可以投靠
Sure. Alright, we can talk later.
当然可以，我们稍后再谈
It's not very comfortable, but it's better than nothing.
虽然不是很舒服，但总比没有好
It's no trouble at all. Thank you.
没关系  谢谢
Nevra...
内芙拉
I didn't know anything. I was completely unaware.
我什么都不知道  我完全不知道
I don't get it. Unaware of what?
我不明白  不知道什么？
Ufuk didn't tell me anything.
乌福克什么都没告诉我
He didn't tell me he was going to burn the house down.
他没有告诉我他要把房子烧掉
He never used to talk, anyway. He was strange. He kept to himself.
总之他以前很少说话，他很奇怪  很自闭
He got much stranger after the fire.
大火过后他变得很陌生
How could I have known he would've burned that house down?
我怎么知道他会把那所房子烧掉？
That the whole family inside would perish in the fire?
他的家人都在大火中丧生吗？
- It was all my fault. - Come on. Take a seat.
-都是我的错  -来吧  坐下说
It's all my fault.
都是我的错
All those children died because of me. I can't bear it.
所有那些孩子都死了，都是因为我，我受不了了
Calm down. Please calm down. Let's wipe your face.
冷静点  请冷静下来  先擦擦眼泪吧
Calm down.
冷静
Can you tell me everything from the start?
你能从头讲起吗？
I hadn't gotten married yet.
我那时还没结婚
I was my father's dear girl. He couldn't bear to see me get married.
我是我父亲的宝贝女儿  他不忍心看到我结婚
- Is he still alive? - No. He passed away.
-他还活着吗？-不，他过世了
- My condolences. - Thank you.
-节哀  -谢谢
I was on my way home from the grocer's. He appeared out of nowhere. Tayyar.
我正从杂货店回家的路上  塔亚尔突然出现
He grabbed me by the arm. Before I knew what was going on,
他抓住我的手臂  在我还没搞清楚情况之前
he took me aside and put a knife against my throat.
他把我拉到一边，用刀对着我的喉咙
Then he...
然后他……
In the trees by my place...
在我家旁边的树林里……
- Did something like that happen again? - Yes.
-之后这种事情又发生了吗？-是的
He told me that if I said anything to anyone he'd humiliate me.
他告诉我，如果我对任何人说起，他就会羞辱我
How could I tell anyone? My father was sick.
我怎么能告诉别人？  当时我父亲病了
And my mom? What was I supposed to tell her?
还有我妈妈  我该怎么开口？
- So you didn't tell anyone anything. - No one.
-所以你没跟任何人说-没有
How did Ufuk find out?
乌福克是怎么发现的？
Tayyar brought Ufuk along one day.
有一天塔亚尔把乌福克带来了
Told me to bed him, as well.
让我也跟他睡
Why would he do that?
他为什么要那样做？
He tricked Ufuk. Took his money. Then told him about this girl.
他骗了乌福克  拿了他的钱  然后告诉他这有个妓女
He brought Ufuk along, but he ran away when he saw me.
他带来了乌福克，但是乌福克见到我就逃走了
He couldn't stomach it. When he realized that I was the girl...
当他意识到我就是那个妓女时，他受不了了
He ran away. He loved me, but I didn't know. That's why he ran.
他逃跑了  他爱我，但我当时不知道那是他逃跑的原因
I realized it too late. The next day, he found me.
我很久以后才知道  第二天，乌福克来找我
Told me not to worry, that he'd handle everything.
告诉我不要担心，他会处理一切
I asked him what he meant.
我问他是什么意思
Then, a week later or so...
然后，大约一周后……
Yes, it was a week later. One night...
是的，这是一周后的一个晚上……
There were these shouts.
喊叫声此起彼伏
Next thing we knew,
接下来人们就知道了
he'd burned the place down.
他把那房子烧了
It was already too late.
已经太晚了
After all that, Ufuk found me again. Told me he'd handled it.
在那之后乌福克又来找过我  说他已经都处理好了
After that day, he never spoke to me again.
那天过后，他再也没有跟我说话
I see.
我懂了
Halis...
哈里斯……
Did you know Halis?
你认识哈里斯吗？
Halis?
哈里斯？
Fireman.
消防员
Oh, Halis. Yes, I knew him. He passed.
哦，哈里斯，我知道他，他去世了
He put it in his report that a cigarette butt started the fire.
他在报告中说是烟头引起了火灾
Why would he do that? Why would he protect Ufuk?
他为什么要这样做？为什么要保护乌福克？
Why would he hide the fact that Ufuk started the fire?
他为什么会掩盖乌福克纵火的事实？
There was this judge.
有这么一个法官
- Mehmet something? - Mehmet Yurtgil.
-穆罕默德 什么的？-穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔
- I don't know his surname. - Mehmet Yurtgil.
-我不知道他的姓氏-穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔
He came and found me. Told me...
他来找我  告诉我……
I wasn't to tell anyone anything.
我没有告诉过任何人
He told me that the family that died was Romani.
他告诉我，死去的一家人是吉普赛人
If it was heard that a Romani family was burned alive in Kambura,
如果别人听说有一家吉普赛人在坎布拉被活活烧死，
no one would care that they were targeted because of me.
没有人会担心他们是因我而死的
Everyone would assume that they were targeted because of their ethnicity.
所有人都会认为他们的死因是种族
That's what he said.
那就是他跟我说的
Some people had forcibly kicked a Romani family out of Kambura.
有人强行将吉普赛一家人赶出坎布拉
He didn't want Kambura to get a bad rap,
他不想让坎布拉名声扫地
so he told me not to say anything. So I said yes.
他告诉我什么都不要说  所以我答应了他
The judge must've spoken to Halis. That's why he said it was a cigarette.
法官一定对哈里斯说过什么，这就是为什么他说是烟头引发的火灾
What else could he have done? Kambura would've gotten a bad rap.
他还能做什么？会有损坎布拉的名誉
Alright.
好的
You rest for now. We can talk again in the morning. OK?
你先休息吧，我们明天早上再谈  可以吗？
Sure. But I've told you everything.
当然可以，但我已经告诉过你一切
What else is there to talk about?
还有什么要谈的？
I don't know anything else.
其他的我什么都不知道
Good morning.
早上好
How are you feeling? Did you sleep well?
感觉怎么样？睡得好吗？
Yes. I slept alright.
是的，我睡得很好
Thanks.
谢谢
Nevra, can you drop me off at the station today?
内芙拉，你今天可以载我去车站吗？
Of course. Are you going back to Kambura?
当然可以  你要回坎布拉吗？
No.
不是
I'm not going back there again.
我不会再回去了
I'm going to go to Bursa. I have relatives there.
我要去布尔萨  那里有亲戚
I see.
明白
Yeliz, I need to ask you something.
叶莉兹  我要问你一件事
The things you told me last night...
你昨晚告诉我的事情……
There's nothing I can do about them as a cop.
作为警察我无能为力
All the people you mentioned are already dead.
你提到的所有人都已经死了
I don't get it.
我不明白
Why did you run from home? Did you come here just to tell me this?
你为什么要从家里跑出来？你来这里只是为了告诉我吗？
You know why?
你知道为什么吗？
I needed to get it off my chest so much.
我需要把这些话说出来
I've kept quiet for years and years.
我多年来一直保持沉默
And after I got married? Forget about it.
结婚之后
My husband figured it out.
我丈夫发现了
When it was time to have sex, he checked and saw that I was a woman.
到了做爱的时候，他检查了一下，发现我不是处女
Well...
好吧……
I thought he'd kick me out then.
我以为他会把我赶出去
I thought he'd leave me. But he really loved me.
我以为他会离开我  但他是真的爱我
He loved me so much. He told me not to explain.
他太爱我了  他告诉我不用解释
"No matter what you did, don't tell me, I don't want to know about it," he said.
他说：“不管你做过什么，都不要告诉我，我也不想知道  ”
So I kept quiet.
所以我保持沉默
Then, when we couldn't have children, it was his turn to keep quiet.
然后，当我们发现不能有孩子时，轮到他保持沉默了
We kept quiet. Husband and wife. Our whole lives.
我们保持沉默的夫妻生活
Keeping a secret makes you feel like you're in prison.
保守秘密会让你觉得自己像是在监狱里
I wanted to get it off my chest. I wanted to get it out of me.
我想把这些话说出来  甩开它
I wanted to finally breathe and be free.
我想自由的呼吸
I hoped it might do some good.
我希望这样可能会有所帮助
But...
但……
You say there's nothing you can do.
你说你无能为力
I'm sorry. I took so much of your time.
对不起，我占用了你很长时间
I've kept you off more urgent business. I'm really sorry. Please forgive me.
我让你错过了更紧急的事情  我真的很抱歉，请原谅
Don't be silly. That's not what I meant.
别傻了  我不是那个意思
I'm glad that you came. I'm glad that you told me all that.
我很高兴你来了  我很高兴你你把这些事情告诉我
Thanks.
谢谢
Thank you for listening to me.
谢谢你听我说
- Have something to eat. - Alright.
-吃点东西-好的
Well, how was our day?
好了，我们今天过得怎么样？
Good. So you liked the tour.
好，所以你喜欢这次旅行
Great. We'll do it again. We certainly will. Don't worry.
太好了  我们再做一次  当然会的  别担心
Feza. Feza.
费扎
Feza. Feza?
费扎？
We'll do it again...
我们会再做一次
We'll arrange good tours.
我们会安排好旅行
Everything was perfect...
一切都很完美
I'm so glad to hear that.
我很高兴听到这个消息
Feza. Feza.
费扎
This way...
这边……
Call if you need anything, alright?
如有需要，打个电话好吗？
Sure. Of course. Thank you so much.
当然可以，非常感谢
You don't have to wait for the bus to leave.
你不必等着车开走
- Have a good journey. - Thank you. Thank you so much.
-旅途愉快  -谢谢  非常感谢你
- Don't. - You aren't checking it?
-不用  -你不坐车了吗？
No.
不
I hate buses. You should skip it, as well.
我讨厌公共汽车  你也别坐了
So, Feza... How about another journey?
那么，费扎  我们去另一个旅行怎么样？
How about another poem?
另外一首诗？
Hello
喂？
Yes.
是
是的
Feza. Come on. We're here.
来吧  费扎  我们到了
Come on.
来吧
It's right there. Just a short walk away. Go on.
就在那儿  几步之遥  加油
This way, Feza. This way.
这边  费扎
Feza? This way.
费扎？这边
This way, Feza.
这边
We're almost there. After these stairs...
就快到了  过了这几个台阶……
We'll turn left, and then...
我们向左转，然后……
Feza, forgive me. I know it was quite a walk.
费扎，原谅我，我知道那是很长的一段路
But the elevator's always broken.
但是电梯总是坏
Always broken. I don't know why.
总是坏  我不知道为什么
Why won't it go in?
为什么不进去呢？
They won't be home.
他们不会回来的
The kids are both out. Don't ring the bell.
孩子们都出去了  别按门铃
Don't ring the bell. There's nobody home.
别按门铃  没有人在家
Feza, there's nobody home. Stop ringing the bell. That's enough.
费扎，没有人在家  别按门铃！
Yes?
谁啊？
Nezaket?
内扎凯特 ？
It's Agah.
我是阿加
Speak louder. I can't hear you.
大声说  我听不到你的声音
Agah.
阿加
Do you remember me?
你还记得我吗？
I used to live here with my wife, Mebrure.
我曾经和我的妻子梅布鲁雷一起住在这里
You were our landlord. Agah Beyoglu.
你是我们的房东  我是阿加·贝尤鲁
Agah Beyoglu.
阿加·贝尤鲁
Agah!
阿加！
Come on in. Come in.
进来进来
So, Agah... You wanted to see your old home?
那么，阿加  你是想看看你的老房子吗？
I understand. It must be full of memories.
我能理解  这里一定充满回忆的
We used to live upstairs, as you know.
如你所知，我们曾经住在楼上
When Fikri died, I took a good look around.
菲克里去世后，我环顾四周
Living on my own in a huge apartment wasn't going to work out.
我自己住在一个巨大的公寓里不行的
So I came down here.
所以我搬下来了
Tell you what.
告诉你吧
Do you remember Iclal? My daughter?
你还记得伊克拉尔吗？我的女儿？
She got married and moved to Ankara.
她结婚后搬到了安卡拉
She never calls me anymore.
她再也没有打电话给我
Why would someone neglect their own mother so much?
为什么会有人这么对待自己的母亲？
Here's how it goes.
这是怎么回事
I call her, she yawns and yawns on the other end.
我打电话给她，她不停的打哈欠
When I ask what's wrong, she tells me she's getting sleepy.
当我问出什么问题时，她告诉我她很困
It baffles me.
这让我感到困惑
When she was a little girl...
当她还是一个小女孩时
I'd swing her for hours, but she wouldn't get a wink of sleep.
我要把她摇摇晃晃几个小时，但她一点都不困
Now, whenever I call to talk, she yawns and yawns.
现在，每当我打电话时，她都会哈欠
When I ask what's wrong, she tells me she's getting sleepy.
当我问出什么问题时，她告诉我她很困
So I stopped calling. What else was I supposed to do?
所以我不再打电话给她  我该怎么办？
I had to accept it.
我不得不接受
So?
那么？
Where do you live now, Agah?
阿加，你现在住在哪里？
Where do you live?
你住在哪里？
- That's what I'm trying to remember. - What's that supposed to mean?
-这就是我试图记起来的  -什么意思？
Don't you know where you live? Where your home is?
你不知道你住在哪里吗？你家在哪里？
- What's Mebrure saying? - That's not Mebrure.
-梅布鲁雷在说什么？-她不是梅布鲁雷
- Excuse me? - That's not Mebrure!
-什么？-她不是梅布鲁雷！
I'm asking myself a different question. Why did I come here?
我在问自己一个不同的问题  我为什么要来这里？
Might I have come here to kill you?
我可能会来这里杀死你吗？
What are you saying? I can't hear you. Speak louder.
你在说什么  我听不到你  大点声
Nezaket, have you ever been to Kambura?
内扎凯特，你去过坎布拉吗？
- What? - Kambura!
-什么？-坎布拉！
Have you ever been to Kambura?
你去过坎布拉吗？
You're losing it.
你疯了
Get off it!
别胡扯！
DOG SLAYER
狗杀手